

🛘 (+1) 8584845307 | 🔀 biehlerj@protonmail.com | 🖸 biehlerj | 😾 biehlerj | 🛅 jacob-biehler-475573139





Sep. 2017 - Dec. 2019

Git

Summary_

Current Software Engineer at Moebius Solutions, Inc. 2+ years of experience as a full-stack software developer, with experience in DevOps with OpenShift and Docker. Super nerd who loves Neovim, Linux, and enjoys to customizing my desktop and development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools as the need arises.

Projects and OSS Contributions _____

- **Conveyor** JavaScript library that helps with automatic dashboard generation.
- Magql Magql is a GraphQL framework for Python. It generates a full-featured, customizable GraphQL API for your data.
- Cointop A fast and lightweight interactive terminal based UI application for tracking cryptocurrencies

Work Experience _____

Moebius Solutions, Inc. San Diego, CA, USA Dec. 2019 - Present JR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER III

• Contributed to open source projects for the company with Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, and Redux,

- Created reactive frontend for managing inventory.
- Developed desktop and mobile application with Electron and Flutter respectively.
- Deployed multiple applications for the customer using OpenShift, Docker, and Jenkins.
- Rewrote frontend for customer using modern frontend practices with TypeScript, React, and Redux.
- · Create plugins for existing Java codebase and add documentation for newly added features using LaTeX.

ScoreShuttle San Diego, CA, USA

JR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2019 - May. 2019

- Added new routes to RESTful API server for credit management service.
- Create administrator tools to manage customer accounts, get better sales data, and allow for 3rd parties to be added to the service.
- Fixed bug in email template to correctly format and send emails to customers.

Education _

Coding School San Francisco, CA, USA

• Learned principles of full-stack software development and DevOps

- Learned systems engineering with C and Python
- · Learned backend web development with Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, and MySQL

• Learned frontend web development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JQuery

Redis

Skills

React

N/A

· Node.js PostgreSQL SQLAlchemy Vagrant IntelliJ

 Virtualbox TypeScript MySQL Flutter (Neo)Vim

Jenkins

 Postman Redux GraphQL CSS Linux

• HTML5

 Insomnia Electron • Python3 Docker Jira

 Visual Studio Fastify Flask OpenShift Code LaTeX

JACOB BIEHLER · RÉSUMÉ OCTOBER 25, 2021